Jan Oledan

Contact Email: jan.oledan@gmail.com Location: Montréal, QC, Canada

Phone: +1 (514) 226-2277 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/joledan

Profile

Early career professional with 5 years of social science research experience in leading academic and international institutions. Expertise in data analysis and visualization using R and STATA. Interested in data for economic development. Fluent in English with a Masters degree in Economics. Dual citizen of Canada and the Philippines.

Education

McGill University

Montréal, QC

M.A. in Economics, specialization in Development Studies Sept 2018–Sept 2019

- Research: Does Online Tutoring Improve Learning Outcomes? Evidence from a Field Experiment Between Canada and Kenya. Supervised by Prof. Matthieu Chemin.
- Seminar paper: Remittances in the Filipino Migrant Context: Why do Migrants Remit?

McGill University

Montréal, QC

B.A. in Economics, minor in Geography

Sept 2015-Apr 2018

Employment

The World Bank

Washington, D.C. (Remote)

Consultant, Development Research Group

July 2020-present

- Contribute to projects about trade, policy, and economic development
- Data analysis (exploratory and causal inference) and visualizations using R and STATA
- Compile data from the World Bank, United Nations, and industry sources
- Write reproducible code and documentation, copy edit and format drafts

Selected projects and supervisors:

- Dr. Tristan Reed: Is the Global Economy Deglobalizing? And If So, Why? And What Is Next? (forthcoming Brookings Papers on Economic Activity), How to End the COVID-19 Pandemic by March 2022, The Falling Price of Cement in Africa (revision requested American Economic Journal: Applied)
- Dr. Lucas Zavala: Trade Barriers, Producer Concentration, and Consumer Welfare in Latin America (ongoing)
- Dr. Devaki Ghose: The Effects of Communal Violence on Women's Marital Outcomes, Million Dollar Plants and Retail Prices

Princeton University

Princeton, NJ

Research Specialist, Empirical Studies of Conflict

May 2019-June 2020

- Supported data projects related to conflict and misinformation
- Managed 20+ research assistants and led data collection of global COVID-19 misinformation
- Wrote and published 4 journalistic-style articles on project findings

Selected projects supervised by Prof. Jacob Shapiro:

• ESOC COVID-19 Misinformation Dataset, Collaborative Models for Understanding Influence Operations: Lessons From Defense Research (Carnegie Endowment for International Peace), COVID-19 Infodemic Monitor (Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists)

McGill University

Montréal, QC May 2018–April 2019

Research Assistant, Political Science

- Assisted data projects on political economy and migration
- Cleaned, geo-coded, and visualized European Union firm-level data using STATA
- Consulted on geospatial data tasks and reviewed ArcPy scripts for land processing

Selected projects supervised by Prof. Leonardo Baccini:

Trade Liberalization and Labor Market Institutions (International Organization),
Economic Determinants of Attitudes toward Migration: Firm-level Evidence from Europe

Other Research Experience

The Research in Color Foundation

Remote

Mentee

Jan 2020–Oct 2020

- Independent research and mentorship program matching scholars of colour with economists. Mentored by Dr. Tristan Reed
- Analyzed the impact of rice tariff laws on local prices in the Philippines

ELIMU Impact Evaluation Unit

Montréal, QC and Kianyaga, KE

Research Intern

May 2017-Aug 2017

- Managed randomized control evaluation of an online English tutoring program to improve schooling outcomes in Kenya. Supervised by Prof. Matthieu Chemin
- Cleaned survey data on English proficiency among student using STATA

Achievements and Awards

Development Studies Award, McGill University, 2018–2019 Graduate Excellence Award, McGill University, 2018–2019 Allan A. Hodgson Arts Internship Award, McGill University, 2017

Code: R, STATA, LATEX, Github (intermediate), Python (intermediate) Programs: RStudio, QGIS, ArcGIS, Microsoft Office

Statistics: Regression analysis, Econometrics, Geospatial data

Personal

Skills

Background: Born in the Philippines, raised in Malaysia, Singapore, United States,

United Kingdom, and Canada

Languages: English, Tagalog, French (intermediate)

Citizenship: Canada and the Philippines

Updated Aug 2023